Guide to the Greater Danbury Intercultural Association Interviews MS064
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Greater Danbury Intercultural Association
1980-1993
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
MS064
2.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains many clippings, administrative materials, and materials related to the different international pavillions. The collection also contains 60 tapes and supporting materials of interviews conducted through by Greater Danbury Intercultural Association to document the contituent groups that make up the greater Danbury area.
Provenance
Likely tranfered to the Archives through Dr. Ellen Rosenbeg. 2016 accretion, gift of Mary Burke.
Access Restrictions
Open for research with some restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Greater Danbury Intercultural Association was created by the City of Danbury in an effort to preserve the heritage of the local people. Dr. Harold Burke was chairman and Andrew DeGrazia was the president. One of Greater Danbury Intercultural Association's projects was to seek out persons from the wide variety of ethnicities that make up the western Connecticut area and interviewing them on topics they felt it was important to preserve regarding their ethnic cultures. That project is present in the forty-six tapes and the five transcripts in our collection. Another project of the Greater Danbury Intercultural Association was the Danbury Ethnic Cultural Festival which ran from 1980 - 1995.
The Danbury Ethnic Cultural Festival was a volunteer project, and related activities/events were free and open to the public. The festivals were annual 3-day events and relied upon volunteer support and the sale of raffle tickets to remain in operation. WCSU was acknowledged as a supporter of the Danbury Ethnic Cultural Festival.
Scope and Content Note
This is a small collection of forty-six tapes, three reel-to-reels, five interview transcripts and newspaper clipping from the Greater Danbury Intercultural Association. The tapes consist of interviews with local immigrants about their heritage. Topics of the interviews include folk tales, language, history, and music. There are five transcribed interviews that correlate with interviews on tape in this collection. [Tape 3 and 11 were blank and removed from the inventory].
In 2016 an accretion to the collection expanded the materials in the collection to include administative materials, clippings, and materials related to the country pavillions that were present at different festivals.
Arrangement
Tapes are arranged in the same order that they were arranged when delivered to the Archives.
The materials are grouped into 4 series:
Missing Title
Administrative Files
International Pavilions and Regional/Ethnic Participation
Audio
Transcripts and Clippings
Related Material
Danbury Remembers – Conversations With a Community: Danbury History Project Oral Histories
Audiotapes.; Oral histories (document genres).; Clippings.; Immigration to the United States.; Danbury (Conn.); Ethnic groups -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Danbury (Conn.) -- History.; Danbury Ethnic Cultural Festival.; Burke, Harold.; Gaffney, Sherry.; DeGrazia, Andrew; Anderson, Beverly.; Schancupp, Barbara.; Shuler, Connie E.; McIlrath, Leo; Metaxas, Nicholas.; Horne, Julia P.
- Administrative Files
  General
  Series includes: Constitutions, original papers of orginization, administrative boards and commitees, legal-permits and orders, financial grants, correspondence, rules and regulation documents, directories of member groups, and procedural directives.
  The financial materials included in this collection were donated to provide evidence that appropriate procedures were followed and to provide examples of the process of maintaining the Intercultural Association and conducting their different activities. All of the printing for the Intercultural Association was performed by a Mr. Connie Shuler, who lived in Danbury during the time, and the Association's bank account was kept with Union Savings Bank - Danbury. After the disolution of the Greater Danbury Intercultural Association the funds remaining in the account were donated to the Danbury Museum and Historical Society.
  - Constitution Rules and Regulations, 1980 (Box 1.1, Folder 1)
  - Board of directors, 1980-1996 (Box 1.1, Folder 2)
  - Permits and grants, 1980-1996 (Box 1.1, Folder 3)
  - Insurance and rental agreements, 1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 4)
  - Agreements-Rogers Park, 1986-1995 (Box 1.1, Folder 5)
  - Festival food rules, 1995 (Box 1.1, Folder 6)
  - Ethnic Festival cook book, undated (Box 1.1, Folder 7)
  - Program material music stage shows, 1985-1993 (Box 1.1, Folder 8)
  - Group directory, 1980-1986 (Box 1.1, Folder 9)
  - Financial reports and statements, 1981-1996 (Box 1.1, Folder 10)
  - Membership forms, 1980-1987 (Box 1.1, Folder 11)
  - Parade Photos, 1980s (Box 1.1, Folder 12)
    ~20 color prints.
  - Women's Center Photos, 1986 (Box 1.1, Folder 13)
    1 color print.
  - Financial Reports, 1980 (Box 1.1, Folder 47)
  - Organizational Information, 1980 (Box 1.1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1.1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1.1, Folder 50)
  - Festival Directories, 1981 (Box 1.1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1.1, Folder 52)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1983 (Box 1.1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1.1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1.1, Folder 55)
  - Programs and Spanish Dance Theater, 1985 (Box 1.1, Folder 56)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 1.1, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence and Announcement, 1986-1987 (Box 1.1, Folder 58)
  - Display of Art and Handiwork G.I.D.A, 1987 (Box 1.1, Folder 59)
  - Map and Programs, 1987 (Box 1.1, Folder 60)
  - Festival Information and Policy, 1989 (Box 1.1, Folder 61)
  - Festival Information and Historical Society, 1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 62)
  - Danbury Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 63)
  - Operational Expenses, 1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 64)
  - Annual Festival Workers' Party, 1991-1993 (Box 1.1, Folder 65)
  - Hatter's Park and Finances, 1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1.1, Folder 67)
  - Festival Programs, 1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 68)
  - Festival Map and Programs, 1993 (Box 1.1, Folder 69)
  - Organizational Information, 1993 (Box 1.1, Folder 70)
  - Financial Records and Pamphlets, 1994 (Box 1.1, Folder 71)
  - Handbook Program, 1995 (Box 1.1, Folder 72)
  - Pamphlet, 1996 (Box 1.1, Folder 73)
  - Entertainment, 1985-1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 74)
  - Student Reports and Intercultural Information, 1982-1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 75)
  - Publicity, 1988-1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 76)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings and Programs, 1982-1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 77)
  - Miscellaneous Festival Materials, 1984-1993 (Box 1.1, Folder 87)
- International Pavilions and Regional/Ethnic Participation
  When the Danbury Intercultural Association began it sent announcements to known ethnic groups in the greater Danbury area. Over time the nature of the relationship between different local ethcnic groups and the Association changed as the members and organization of different local ethnic related groups changed. Collaboration with the Greater Danbury Intercultural Association was also an opportunity for lesser known ethnic groups to gain recognition within the community, while it also provided a platform for all associated groups to host their own events.
  - Countries
    - African American Pride, 1986 (Box 1.1, Folder 14)
      3 color photographs
    - Alliance Francaise, Undated (Box 1.1, Folder 15)
      One pamphlet
    - Americana, 1982-1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 16)
      Newspaper clipping, Copy of ten dollar bill from 1776, a pamphlet, threee color photographs.
    - Baha'i Faith, 1986 (Box 1.1, Folder 17)
      1 color photograph
    - Brazil, 1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 18)
      1 newspaper article, 2 pamphlets, 1 color photo
    - Cambodia, 1990-1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 19)
      3 newspaper clippings
    - Children's Palace, 1990-1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 20)
      2 color photos and mixed materials
    - China, 1981-1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 21)
      1 color photo and newspaper clippings
    - Colombia, 1993 (Box 1.1, Folder 22)
    - Dominicana, 1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 23)
      One flyer
    - Friends of the Library, Undated (Box 1.1, Folder 24)
      One color photo
    - Germany, 1986-1987 (Box 1.1, Folder 25)
      3 color photos
    - Greece, 1986 (Box 1.1, Folder 26)
      1 newspaper picture
    - India, 1982-1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 27)
    - Indonesia, Undated (Box 1.1, Folder 28)
      One newspaper clipping
    - Ireland, Undated (Box 1.1, Folder 29)
      pamphlet, three color phots, receipt
    - Italy, 1984-1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 30)
      9 color photos and button
    - Jamaica, Undated (Box 1.1, Folder 31)
      Recipe for red beans, rice, and ginger beer
    - Jewish Federation, undated (Box 1.1, Folder 32)
    - Laos, 1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 33)
      1 newspaper clipping
    - Lebanon, 1985-1995 (Box 1.1, Folder 34)
      One color photo, newspaper clipping, and mixed materials
    - Mexico, 1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 35)
      Two color photos
    - Native America, 1991 (Box 1.1, Folder 36)
      Three color photos
    - Norwegian, 1989 (Box 1.1, Folder 37)
      One newspaper article
    - Philippines, Undated (Box 1.1, Folder 38)
      Three color photographs and mixed materials
    - Portugal, 1983-1992 (Box 1.1, Folder 39)
      Six color photgraphs and mixed materials
    - Russia, 1980 (Box 1.1, Folder 40)
      Group Financial Report
    - Senior Center, 1986 (Box 1.1, Folder 41)
      2 color photos
    - Southeast Asia, 1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 42)
      newpaper article
    - Sweeden, undated (Box 1.1, Folder 43)
    - Taiwan, undated (Box 1.1, Folder 44)
    - Tibet, undated (Box 1.1, Folder 45)
    - Ukraine, 1985 (Box 1.1, Folder 46)
  - Photographs
    All photographs by Mary J. Burke.
    - Parade Photos, ca. 1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 78-81)
    - Group Photos, ca. 1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 82-83)
    - Festival Booths, ca. 1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 84)
    - Festival Performances, ca. 1990 (Box 1.1, Folder 85-86)
- Audio, OH_002___x
  General note
  The Greater Danbury Intercultural Association oral history project lead them to seek out persons from the wide variety of ethnicities that make up the western Connecticut area and interview them about their heritage, their lives, and on topics they felt were important to preserve regarding their cultures.
  That project resulted in the forty-six tapes and five transcripts in this collection.
  - German Language W. Tallent; Lebanese History A. Hajj; Portugese Painter Louiz Dos Santos, undated; OH_002_1_1A_x (Box 1, Item 1A)
  - Norwegian Fram; Tour of Campsite Delancy Brigade Bev. (Women); Olde Tyme Fiddlers, undated; OH_002_1_1B_x (Box 1, Item 1B)
  - Julius Tulipani - Interview Italian - Ridgefield, undated; OH_002_1_2A_x (Box 1, Item 2A)
  - Julius Tulipani - Interview Italian - Ridgefield, undated; OH_002_1_2B_x (Box 1, Item 2B)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_4A_x (Box 1, Item 4A)
  - Italian Folk Tales Andrew de Grazia, undated; OH_002_1_4B_x (Box 1, Item 4B)
  - How Red Feather and Field Mouse Discovered Maple Sugar [retold from Anishineabemowin by retold by Keewaydinoquay], 1982; OH_002_1_5A_x (Box 1, Item 5A)
    Side 1= 21:02 min; side 2 =18:49 min
  - Italian Language Lesson - Frank Zappala, undated; OH_002_1_6A_x (Box 1, Item 6A)
  - Italian Language, undated; OH_002_1_6B_x (Box 1, Item 6B)
  - Judith Cook Tucker - Musical Exporation of many nations, undated; OH_002_1_7A_x (Box 1, Item 7A)
  - Hindi - Roopa Goswami, undated; OH_002_1_7B_x (Box 1, Item 7B)
  - Italian Frank Zappala, undated; OH_002_1_8A_x (Box 1, Item 8A)
  - Gaelic John Joyce, undated; OH_002_1_8B_x (Box 1, Item 8B)
  - Norwegian Bebery Anderson (Films), undated; OH_002_1_9A_x (Box 1, Item 9A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_9B_x (Box 1, Item 9B)
  - Keewaydinoquay, an Ojibwa from Michigan talks about Indian Healing, undated; OH_002_1_10B_x (Box 1, Item 10A)
    30:36 Min.
    From the Tape Sleeve:
    Keewaydinoquay, an Ojibwa from Michigan, will meet visitors and talk about Indian healing tommorrow at 1:30 PM in the American Indian Archaeological Institute, Route 199, Washington, Conn.
    Keewaydinoquay, "Woman-of-the-Northwest-Wind", is a member of the Crane Clan of the Anishinaabeg Nation. Apprenticed at the age of nine to an Ojibwa mahkwe, she was intitiated into Midewiwin, the Ojibwa medicine society. She has practiced healing for more than 50 years. Admission is by donation.
  - Shingabiss: A Merry-Hearted Tale of Self Reliance told by Anishinaabemowin (cont.), undated; OH_002_1_10A_x (Box 1, Item 10B)
    Native American oral folktale about the Shingabiss, a creature who was orphaned and doesn't know how to prepare for winter retold by Keewaydinoquay.
  - Ukranian History - Pearl Dent - Olga Poproski, undated; OH_002_1_12A_x (Box 1, Item 12A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_12B_x (Box 1, Item 12B)
  - Irish - Mary Hearty (Poetry), undated; OH_002_1_13A_x (Box 1, Item 13A)
  - Irish (Cont.), Jewish Literature, undated; OH_002_1_13B_x (Box 1, Item 13B)
  - Converstaions of De Grazia, undated; OH_002_1_14A_x (Box 1, Item 14A)
  - Cont. Converstaions of De Grazia, undated; OH_002_1_14B_x (Box 1, Item 14B)
  - English Translation - Norweigan Folk Tales (a)Three Billy Goats Gruff b) Parson and the Sexton c) How the Bear Got its Short Tale d) The Man who Wanted to do Women's Work, undated; OH_002_1_15A_x (Box 1, Item 15A)
  - Blank, undated; OH_002_1_15B_x (Box 1, Item 15B)
  - Fr. Medynski - St. Gregory's Boys Choir - DeLancy Brigade - Phylis Zaretsky, undated; OH_002_1_16A_x (Box 1, Item 16A)
  - L. Peterson - Portugese weaver - Judith Cook Tucker, undated; OH_002_1_16B_x (Box 1, Item 16B)
  - Squeal, undated; OH_002_1_17A_x (Box 1, Item 17A)
  - Squeal, undated; OH_002_1_17B_x (Box 1, Item 17B)
  - Irish Mary Harty - Duel of Cuchullian, How to Catch a Leprachaun, undated; OH_002_1_18A_x (Box 1, Item 18A)
  - Greek Nick Metaxas - A Part of my Live During the War, undated; OH_002_1_18B_x (Box 1, Item 18B)
  - New Hope Baptist Cruse-Jackson Bowma, undated; OH_002_1_19A_x (Box 1, Item 19A)
  - New Hope Baptist Cruse-Jackson Bowma (Cont.), undated; OH_002_1_19B_x (Box 1, Item 19B)
  - Many Nations - Judith Cook Tucker Musical Exploration, undated; OH_002_1_20A_x (Box 1, Item 20A)
  - German Erika Eckert - Reading of Original Works, undated; OH_002_1_20B_x (Box 1, Item 20B)
  - Opening Ceremony, 1981; OH_002_1_21A_x (Box 1, Item 21A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_21B_x (Box 1, Item 21B)
  - De Grazia, undated; OH_002_1_22A_x (Box 1, Item 22A)
  - De Grazia, undated; OH_002_1_22B_x (Box 1, Item 22B)
  - Jewish Lit. Cont. Music - Outdoors of Stage Show, undated; OH_002_1_23A_x (Box 1, Item 23A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_23B_x (Box 1, Item 23B)
  - Jewish Lit. Readings, undated; OH_002_1_24A_x (Box 1, Item 24A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_24B_x (Box 1, Item 24B)
  - Urdu Lang Tanira and Zafar Naqui, undated; OH_002_1_25A_x (Box 1, Item 25A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_25B_x (Box 1, Item 25B)
  - New Hope Baptist Church - Mildred Jackson - Forrista bowman, undated; OH_002_1_26A_x (Box 1, Item 26A)
  - Jackson - Bowman, undated; OH_002_1_26B_x (Box 1, Item 26B)
  - German History - Film; Greek Slide - A. Cambetes, undated; OH_002_1_27A_x (Box 1, Item 27A)
  - Cont. Greek Slides - Cambetes; Norwegian Hist. (Film), undated; OH_002_1_27B_x (Box 1, Item 27B)
  - The Real Story of the Vikings - Anderson/Gaffrey, undated; OH_002_1_28A_x (Box 1, Item 28A)
  - Italian Poety - Paolo M., undated; OH_002_1_28B_x (Box 1, Item 28B)
  - Commentary Slides representing the history and geography of the Ukraine, Short segment on Ukrainian Easter eggs, etc., undated; OH_002_1_29A_x (Box 1, Item 29A)
  - Commentary Slides - Olga, undated; OH_002_1_29B_x (Box 1, Item 29B)
  - German Language Lesson, undated; OH_002_1_30A_x (Box 1, Item 30A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_30B_x (Box 1, Item 30B)
  - Three King's Day - Spanish, undated; OH_002_1_31A_x (Box 1, Item 31A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_31B_x (Box 1, Item 31B)
  - History and Cult Fest - Indian Mimic?, undated; OH_002_1_32A_x (Box 1, Item 32A)
  - Meeting - A. DeGrazia, undated; OH_002_1_32B_x (Box 1, Item 32B)
  - Norwegian - Arnt Tonnessen and Spanish - Tom Doyle, undated; OH_002_1_33A_x (Box 1, Item 33A)
  - Spanish Lesson, German [lesson?] - William Tallent, undated; OH_002_1_33B_x (Box 1, Item 33B)
  - Russian Language - Yana Rodin, undated; OH_002_1_34A_x (Box 1, Item 34A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_1_34B_x (Box 1, Item 34B)
  - German Poetry - Prepared by Erika Eckert Presented by Margaret Schemmel, undated; OH_002_1_35A_x (Box 1, Item 35A)
  - German Poetry - Prepared by Erika Eckert Presented by Margaret Schemmel, undated; OH_002_1_35B_x (Box 1, Item 35B)
  - The Jewish community - Rhoda Malino, undated; OH_002_1_36A_x (Box 1, Item 36A)
  - Portugese Lang. Edmund Souza, undated; OH_002_1_36B_x (Box 1, Item 36B)
  - Irish History- DBY/Bethel Ed Gallagher, undated; OH_002_2_37A_x (Box 2, Item 37A)
    Case only; tape missing
  - German History - German America - Tim Duskin, undated; OH_002_2_37B_x (Box 2, Item 37B)
  - German William Tallent, undated; OH_002_2_38A_x (Box 2, Item 38A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_2_38B_x (Box 2, Item 38B)
  - Luiz Dos Santos, Portugese Sculptor, undated; OH_002_2_39A_x (Box 2, Item 39A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_2_39B_x (Box 2, Item 39B)
  - Irish Dancing, Iris Grey, undated; OH_002_2_40A_x (Box 2, Item 40A)
  - Irish Dancing, Iris Grey (Cont.), undated; OH_002_2_40B_x (Box 2, Item 40B)
  - Sophie Trudel - Indonesia, undated; OH_002_2_41A_x (Box 2, Item 41A)
  - Sophie Trudel - Indonesia, undated; OH_002_2_41B_x (Box 2, Item 41B)
  - Delia Keane (Irish) 100 Years Old, undated; OH_002_2_42A_x (Box 2, Item 42A)
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_2_42B_x (Box 2, Item 42B)
  - DeGrazia Side I, undated; OH_002_2_43A_x (Box 2, Item 43A)
  - DeGrazia Side II, undated; OH_002_2_43B_x (Box 2, Item 43B)
  - Greek History, undated; OH_002_2_44A_x (Box 2, Item 44A)
  - Interview Triantafelidis, undated; OH_002_2_44B_x (Box 2, Item 44B)
  - Broadway Pop Choir Directed by Connie Swanson, undated; OH_002_2_45A_x (Box 2, Item 45A)
  - Italian Rebhan Nassif Dancers: Tarantella Dances Girl Scouts Troop 303 Norwalk Double Dutch, Spiritual Songs, undated; OH_002_2_45B_x (Box 2, Item 45B)
  - Hunting Whales (1932) Arnt Tonnessen (Norway), undated; OH_002_2_46A_x (Box 2, Item 46A)
  - Norwegian Folk Tales (Arnt Tonnessen narrator), undated; OH_002_2_46B_x (Box 2, Item 46B)
  - Interview Frank Esposito, undated; OH_002_2_47A_x (Box 2, Item 47A)
    Frank Esposito 93? y.o. Born San Bernardo De Collututa region Calabria Italy
  - [no tape label description], undated; OH_002_2_47B_x (Box 2, Item 47B)
  - Irish Speaker: John Boyle, State Historian - Ancient Order of Hibernians, The History of the Irish, undated; OH_002_2_48A_x (Box 2, Item 48A)
  - Polish Polish People and Churches in the Danbury Areas (Oral Presentation), undated; OH_002_2_48B_x (Box 2, Item 48B)
- Transcripts and Clippings, OH_002___x
  This series contains transcripts of five of the oral history interviews conducted with local persons by the Greater Danbury Intercultural Association and some miscellaneous materials related to the annual Intercultural Festival.
  - Oral History Interview with Arnt Tonnessen, undated; OH_002_3_1_x (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Transcript by Nancy Morris; Norwegian Folk Tales
  - Oral Interview with Julius Tulipani, undated; OH_002_3_2_x (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Transcript By Nancy Morris; Julius Tulipani was a Former Selectman of Ridgefield
  - Oral Interview with Frank Esposito, undated; OH_002_3_3_x (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Italian History; Transcript
  - Oral Interview with Ed Gallagher, undated; OH_002_3_4_x (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Irish History; Transcript
  - Oral Interview with Mr. Triantafelidis, undated; OH_002_3_5_x (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Greek History; Transcript
  - Danbury Ethnic Cultural Festival Miscellaneous, undated; OH_002_3_6_x (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Newspaper clippings, Financial Appeal/Assistance letters, Festival Program